Niizuma
Eiji Ltd
What?!
最終回を描き始めるまで1位だったら 連載を終わりにする
You'll end it if you're still in first place when you start your final chapter,
10週連続じゃなくて
and not after ten weeks instead?
はい そう変わったと編集長にお伝え下さい
Yes. Please inform the Chief Editor of the change.
えーっと それって16週連続1位取るって事
So, that means you're aiming to get first place for 16 weeks in a row?
福田組の皆さんにそう宣言しました
That's what I announced to Team Fukuda.
Then they said they'd go for first place
themselves to stop me from ending CROW.
そしたら「自分たちが1位を取って『CROW』を終わらせない」と言われました
よりやる気が出ました
I'm even more motivated now.
絶対に負けません
I'm definitely not losing to any of them!
新妻君 この話他の編集にもしていいか
Niizuma, would you mind if I told the other editors about this?
どういう事です
What do you mean?
この話をすれば 編集部全員が新妻君以外に1位を取らせ
If I tell them about this, all the editors will try to prevent you from ending CROW
「CROW」を終わらせるのを阻止しようとするだろう
by helping someone else take first place.
もちろん 僕も「CROW」を終わらせたくない
That includes me, of course.
I don't want you to end CROW.
どうぞ 言って下さい
Go right ahead.
編集部全員 敵
The entire editing department is my enemy!
This is good! I'm getting more and more excited!
いいです
ますます燃えてきたです
yu
me
Dreams, dreams, dreams, dreams
ka
na
e
ru
ta
bi
ko
wa
re
te
yu
ku
me
As soon as I reach my goals, it all falls through again
na
ze
so
re
de
mo
ma
ta
So why do I run...
bo
ku
wa
sa
ga
su
ha
shi
ri
tsu
zu
ke
ru
...and search in spite of that?
hi
sa
shi
bu
ri
ni
de
atta
We met after such a long time
"
fu
n
i
ki
ka
watta?"
"Has the mood changed for us?"
tsu
ki
hi
wa
na
ga
re
ta
da
rou
So much time has passed
"
a
no
ko
ro
no
ho
u
ga
ta
no
shi
so
u
"
"It seemed like more fun back then"
ta
ku
sa
n
na
ku
shi
ta
We've lost so much
so
n
na
ko
to
wa
ki
zu
i
te
ru
n
da
I already know that, though
sa
ke
bi
tsu
zu
ke
ro
mo
ga
ki
tsu
zu
ke
ro
Don't stop screaming, don't stop struggling
da
re
no
ta
me
ni
na
n
ka
mou
i
da
rou?
You've done enough for others
ma
da
tsu
ta
e
i
ko
to
ga
a
ru
ma
da
I still, still have something I haven't told you yet
yu
me
no
sa
ki
ni
wa
yu
me
shi
ka
na
i
Beyond each of my dreams lies yet another dream
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)出品 仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
---诸神字幕组---
台本: 共由         翻译: 新人&poopy       繁化: 烨语
校对：绫女       时间轴：Color
Front and Center
Days of the week
May
Assistants in
Manuscript up
えっと「CROW」残り12話でエイジが最終話を描くのが10週先だとすると
Um... so CROW would have 12 chapters left,
and if we assume it'll be 10 weeks
before Eiji starts on his final chapter...
May 14, Saturday
7週の勝負か
That'll give us seven weeks to compete with him.
そうだな
Yeah.
今週分もきっと1位だろうし
He'll probably get first place this week too.
first place
入稿済みの来週分と 今描いてる分が1位なら
If what he's sent to the publisher for next week and what he's currently drawing both get first place,
first place
チャンスはあと7回
that only leaves us with seven more opportunities.
first place
「抜いてみせる」って言ったけど 簡単じゃないよな
We said we'd pass him, but it's not as easy as it sounds!
面白いです
How interesting.
あと5週なんて言いません
Forget five weeks.
僕が最終回の原稿を描く前に 誰であろうと一度でも抜いた人がいたら
If anyone manages to beat me even once before I start my final manuscript,
I won't end CROW!
「CROW」はやめません
勝負です
It's a challenge!
でも 抜きたい
But... I want to beat him!
「CROW」を終わらせる
He's planning to end CROW?
そんなの駄目に決まってるだろ
He can't do that!
会社の利益的にも
It's not good for the company, either!
いや 僕だって終わらせたくないですよ
Well, it's not like I want that to happen, you know.
I think it's best for both the author and the manga to let the author choose when to end it, though.
でも 終わらせたいというところで終わらせてあげた方が
作家や作品のためだと僕は思いますけど
甘いな
Don't be naive!
商業誌に載ってる時点で 作品は作家だけのものじゃないんだ
From the moment a manga is printed in a magazine,
it's no longer the author's sole property.
中野さん どこまで会社人間なんですか
Are you really that much of a corporate stooge, Nakano?
何を
What was that?!
会社のためなんて事以前に 新妻君のためにも「CROW」はまだ描かすべきだ
Before you start talking about what's best for the company,
you should think first about what's best for Niizuma, and that's to keep drawing!
「CROW」はまだまだ伸びしろのあるこれからの作品
CROW is a manga that can be further developed!
新妻君も まだ若い
Niizuma is still young!
今が一番の伸び盛り
Now's the ideal time for him to develop!
It's your job as his editor to maximize his potential!
作家の能力を最大限に引き出すのが担当の仕事だろ
より魅力のある より読者に喜んでもらえる雑誌作り
Keeping the readers happy and making the magazine even more appealing!
If you remember those basic principles of our job as editors,
編集者としての原点に戻り 考えれば
「CROW」を終わらせるなんてありえない
then it's unthinkable that we'd
ever consider letting him end CROW.
そのとおり 新妻君も「CROW」も伸びる ここで終わらすな
That's right! Both Niizuma and CROW can still gain greater heights!
Don't let him end it here!
雄二郎 新妻君を説得してるのか
Yuujirou, have you tried talking him out of it yet?
説得も何も 編集長が新妻君の要求をのんじゃってるんですから
What good would that do? The Chief
Editor himself agreed to his demand.
だったら 誰かが「CROW」を抜くしかないわけか
In that case, someone else has to surpass CROW.
でも 今の「CROW」を抜くのは正直難しいんじゃ
Quite frankly, that's gonna be pretty tough to pull off.
いや だからこそだ
No, that's exactly why it has to be done!
これで 担当の作家に抜かせたら 表彰ものだ
Whoever gets their author to surpass CROW will get bragging rights!
もちろん その表彰を受けるのはこの吉田だが
Of course, I fully intend to get those.
いいや 今回は僕が
No, this time I'll get them!
いいえ 僕です
No, me!
あと7話で勝負って事は
A seven chapter competition means...
We could do a four chapter arc and a three chapter arc,
4話のシリーズと3話のシリーズにしてラストを盛り上げて1位を取りにいく
and build them up to a climax in the final chapters to get first place!
いや それじゃ駄目だと思う
No, I don't think that'd work.
駄目
You don't?
今まで何度もやってきたやり方だし
That's the way we've always done it,
それで一度も「CROW」の上に行った事ないだろ
and yet we've never surpassed CROW even once.
そうなると どうすれば
In that case, what should we do?
I think we need to be more unorthodox.
俺は より邪道にするしかないと思う
より邪道に
More unorthodox?
そう
Yes.
「CROW」は典型的な王道バトル
CROW is a typical standard battle manga.
「PCP」を邪道って考えると読み味の違い
The main stylistic difference between our works is that PCP is unorthodox.
邪道をもっと強くして そこで勝負すべき
That's why we should go all out on making it even more unorthodox.
I see.
なるほど
でも より邪道って 具体的にどうやって
How do we go about doing that, though?
次に描く「邪道な王道バトル」
Remember that "unorthodox standard battle manga" we were planning to make next?
Let's try that idea out here.
そのアイデアをここで試す
Takahama
編集部としても「CROW」は終わらせたくない
The editing department doesn't want to see CROW end.
ここは何としても
We have to somehow—
抜いてみせます
I'll surpass him!
Ashirogi Mutou...
亜城木夢叶 新妻エイジ
Niizuma Eiji...
Surpassing them has always been my goal!
彼らを超えるのは僕がずっと掲げてきた目標ですから
I'll go up against them with this next arc that I've been thinking about for a while.
次のシリーズ いつかやろうと思って温めてきた話をぶつけます
Yeah!
この新キャラはいい
I like this old guy as a new character.
爺さんの集める仲間も
And these friends he gathers, too!
GIRIにほれ込んだ伝説のレーサー
He's a legendary racer who takes a liking to GIRI.
The old guy and his friends team up with GIRI,
この爺さんと仲間たちがチームを組んで
幻のライディングテクニックをGIRIに伝授する
then teach him a legendary driving technique!
想像を絶する秘密特訓
An unimaginable, secret training regimen!
そして 幻のテクをものにした時与えられる
And once he's learned the legendary technique...
He gets a new bike!
ニューマシン
いけます 先生 最高っす
That'll be sweet!
Awesome!
完璧っす
It's perfect!
だよな
I know, right?!
An appealing new character raises your manga's popularity.
人気を取るには魅力ある新キャラ これは基本だ
That's a basic rule.
それプラスニューマシン
That, plus a new bike too!
これなら「CROW」の上も夢じゃない
With this, surpassing CROW isn't just a dream anymore!
夢って何だよ 現実にしてやるぜ
"Dream"? I'll turn it into reality!
うっそー
No way!
僕に1位を取れと
Me?! Get first place?!
そうだ
Yes.
無理に決まってるじゃないですか
That's impossible, of course!
吉田氏も「ギャグマンガで1位は到底無理だ」と
You even told me before that it's impossible for a gag manga to get first place!
いつも言ってるじゃないですか
そう まだギャグマンガ
Yes, if you were still doing a gag manga, that is.
だが これから「僕には通じない」を
However, starting now,
笑いあり 涙ありのストーリーマンガにしていく
you're going to remake Never Reaching You into a plot-driven manga full of laughter and tears.
僕は最初からそのつもりで描いてるんですけどね
That's what I've been trying to do from the beginning, though.
なのに なぜ作品はギャグにしか見えないか 分かるか
Why does it seem like a gag manga, then?
Do you know?
いえ なぜですか
No.
Why?
It's the art!
Ugh, I'm
running late.
Gulp,
I feel sick.
I'm about to
throw up.
絵だ
絵
The art?!
このキャラではギャグにしか見えんのだ
With characters like these, of course it's going to seem like a gag manga!
絵を5週以内で改革し
You're going to transform the art within the next five weeks to turn it into a serious, negative love story.
シリアスネガティブ・ラブストーリーマンガにしていく
し しかし絵だけはそう簡単には
B-But you can't change the art that easily—
中井君がいるだろう
You have Nakai.
彼のデッサン力は確かだ
His sketching abilities are the real thing.
No! I refuse to be taught by him!
嫌だ
あいつに教わるのだけは
そんなに嫌か
Are you that against it?
嫌だ
I am!
あっ アイデアが
I just got an idea.
メモメモ
Need to write it down...
よし ネガティブ要素は中井君を「先生」と呼ばせる事でバッチリだ
Good. It looks like he got the right amount of
negativity from the thought of calling Nakai "Sensei".
あとは
All that's left is...
山久 そっちはどうだ
Yamashita, how's it going at your end?
Erm, yes.
ああ はい
話し合った結果
We came to the conclusion
「冒険するより今の順位を守りながら確実に」という話に
that instead of taking a risk, we'll just work to preserve and maintain her current rank.
そうか 蒼樹先生は「是非 平丸先生に1位を取ってもらいたい」と
I see.
So Aoki said that she definitely wants Hiramaru to try and go for first place.
Oh? She said that if he did that, she'd
think that he's really cool and amazing?
それをやったら「平丸さん超かっこいい ステキ」だって
そんな事言ってませんけど
I didn't say any of those things.
まあ 平丸先生の力になれる事があれば言ってほしいとは
Well, she did say that she'd like to help Hiramaru in any way she can.
そうか 平丸君が1位取ったら
I see.
So she said that if Hiramaru got first place, she'll grant any one wish of his, huh?
蒼樹先生は平丸君の願いを何でも一つ聞いてくれると言ってるのか
ひ 平丸です
Th-This is Hiramaru.
蒼樹さんに代わってもらえますか
Could you please hand it over to Aoki?
どうしたんですか 平丸さん
What is it, Hiramaru?
「カズタン」と
...Kazu.
What?
もし1位を取ったら ぼ 僕を「カズタン」と呼んで下さい
If I get first place, can you start calling me "Kazu" instead?!
「カズタン」ですか
Kazu, is it?
分かりました
Okay.
キャー やったー
All right!
吉田氏 絶対1位取りましょう
Mr. Yoshida, let's get first place, no matter what!
そんなんでいいのか
Please call me Kazu!
That's all he wanted?
悪役の新キャラ
A new villain?
でも これって
He seems more like a protagonist, though.
主人公キャラっぽいというか
そう ずっと考えてたんだけど
Yes.
I've been thinking about this.
王道バトルの主人公になりえるかっこいいキャラ
A cool character who seems like he'd be the protagonist of a standard battle manga.
If we use him in an unorthodox standard battle manga,
それを使って邪道な王道バトルにするには
そのキャラを悪のヒーローにする事だと思う
we should make him more of an "evil hero", I think.
悪のヒーローか
An evil hero, huh?
模倣犯の時思ったけど
During the copycat arc, I realized that
characterization makes a villain stand out.
悪役ってキャラ立つじゃん
You stole the
textbooks from
everyone and hid
them in the gym
storage room.
Hmph!
Of course
you got caught.
You put out a notice
of intent to steal.
If it had gone
successfully, it would
look like PCP had done
it, and you'd have
been gloating over your
copycat crime.
PCP wouldn't
have hidden
them in such
a place.
Akechi...
when did
you realize
that I was
the culprit,
and not PCP?
I knew from
the beginning
that it wasn't
PCP.
確かに この前のは生徒の一人だから 悪役としてはイマイチだったけど
Yeah. In that arc, the antagonist was just a lone
student who couldn't be considered much of a villain.
次に出すのは普通の犯罪者じゃなくて
The next villain we make shouldn't be an ordinary criminal.
何て言うか
He should be like...
怪人二十面相みたいな
the "Fiend with 20 Faces," or something like that.
That's good!
いいよ それ
姿すら現さないけど PCPに駄目だししたり
He won't show his face, but he'll judge PCP
時にはアドバイスまでしてくれる
and give them advice sometimes!
I've got an image in mind!
イメージ出来てきた
止まんねえ
I'm on a roll now!
明日には文章原作にしてくるよ
I'll make it into a script by tomorrow!
Oh! This is the introduction of a new character, right?
ここで新キャラの登場か
敵か味方か それすら分からない
You can't even tell if he's a friend or an enemy.
正体を追い続けるPCP
PCP's trying to find out his identity.
面白い
This is good!
Σってネーミングも悪くない
Naming him "Sigma" was a good idea.
サンキュー
Thanks.
よし ネームはこれでいい
Okay, the storyboard is fine as it is.
この新キャラで新妻君と勝負だ
Let's go up against Niizuma with this new character!
はい
Right!
このマシンのデザイン 鳥山先生っすか
This bike's design... Is it from Toriyama?
やっぱ 分かる
You can tell?
えっと 冤罪事件の資料は確かここに
Um... The documents on the false
charges case were over here, I think.
デッサンがなってないんだよ
That's not good enough for a rough sketch! Not good enough!
デッサンが
はい 中井先生
Yes, Nakai-sensei.
May 27, Friday
24 25号と「CROW」に1位を取られたが
CROW took top spot in Issues 24 and 25.
But the real showdown is in Issue 26 here.
明暗を分けるのはこの26号だ
はい
Right.
うわ 「GIRI」も新キャラ
Whoa! GIRI has a new character, too!
ひ 平丸さん絵がうまくなってる
H-Hiramaru's art got better!
ほんとだ
You're right!
You can tell that more enthusiasm than usual was put into most of the manga here.
ほとんどの作品がいつもより気合いが入っているように見える
新妻君の影響だな
It's Niizuma's influence.
いけるよな
This'll do it.
はい
Yes.
勝ちっす
We'll win!
How's this for an art change?
どうだ この絵の変わりようは
平丸君 よくやった
You did well, Hiramaru.
君は努力しないだけで やればできる人だ
You're not a hard worker, but you can do anything once you put your back into it.
全ては「カズタン」のために
It's all so she'll call me "Kazu"...
シリーズの第1話 ここで食いついてもらえれば
The first chapter of the arc... If I can reel people in with this...
これで絶対エイジの上に
We'll definitely rank higher than Eiji with this!
June 3, Friday
「PCP」 今週の本ちゃん
PCP was 4th this week.
4位だ
「CROW」はまた1位
CROW placed 1st again.
くっそー
Dammit.
Σ初登場の話数でも駄目か
The chapter introducing Sigma wasn't enough.
そんなに悲観する事もない
There's no need to be so disappointed.
票数だけ見れば
Going by the vote counts, PCP's went up by 21.
「PCP」は21票上がっている
What?
他にも票を上げた作品が多い
There were many other manga whose vote counts increased.
逆に「CROW」は33票下げている
Conversely, CROW's dropped by 33.
それだと 「CROW」との差は100票以内になったって事ですか
So that means we're within 100 votes of CROW?
Seigi no Mikata
Road Racer GIRI
福田君や高浜君たちも頑張ってるから
Because Fukuda, Takahama, and the others are so trying hard,
「CROW」の票が分散してその分1位を取るチャンスも増えるって事だ
CROW's votes got split up, increasing the chances of getting first place.
なんか 人頼みなところもあるけどなぁ
It seems like we're just relying on others, then.
そんな事ないよ
That's not true.
1位を取ればそれが一番面白いマンガ それは間違いない
The manga that gets first place is the best manga.
There's no mistaking that.
Yes.
そうだな 編集部もそわそわしだしてきている
The editing department is getting anxious as well.
そわそわ
Anxious?
どの作品が「CROW」を抜いて1位を取るか
Over which manga will take the top spot and defeat CROW.
ち ちなみに編集部での予想は
B-By the way, which one does the editing department think is the front-runner?
今のところは「正義の三肩」だ
Right now,
it's Seigi no Mikata.
主人公の検事アキラと刑事ヒロトとの友情物語
It's a tale of friendship between the protagonists—
a prosecutor named Akira and a detective named Hiroto.
新シリーズはドラマとしてよく出来ている
The new drama is well done.
The Complete Book
of the Six Codes
Trial Records
The Complete Book of the Six Codes
残念だが 今週も6位だ
Unfortunately, you're 6th again this week.
いけますよ 港浦さん
I can do it, Miura.
シリーズ導入部で6位
The beginning of the arc coming in at 6th place.
予想どおりです
It's just as I predicted.
It's going to get more exciting from here on,
これから どんどん盛り上がっていきますから
巻頭カラーの号で1位狙えます
and I'll go for first place with the issue
where I have a front cover color spread.
おう そうだな
Yeah, you're right!
このシリーズなら
This arc can...
身に覚えのない事件の容疑がかけられた刑事ヒロト
Detective Hiroto, charged as a suspect with no memory of the incident.
ヒロトをよく知るアキラは彼のはずがないと思いながらも
Akira, who knows Hiroto well and is confident of his innocence, is nevertheless put in charge of exposing his crimes.
罪を暴かなくてはならない立場に立たされ
悩みながらも 親友を被告とした裁判に検事として臨む
While conflicted, he faces a trial in
which he must prosecute his best friend.
And the final chapter will reveal a shocking plot twist with an overturned verdict.
そして ラストは大どんでん返しの逆転判決
なるほど
I see.
一番盛り上がる話を巻頭カラーに
So, the climax of his arc will happen when he gets the front cover?
やるな
Nice one.
逆に「正義の三肩」はここで1位を取らないとつらいだろうな
On the other hand, it'd be tough to
swallow if he doesn't get first place there.
じゃ じゃあ その次あたり「PCP」も巻頭カラーに
C-Can PCP get the front cover spread after that, then?
いや そこは「ロードレーサーGIRI」に決まった
No, Road Racer GIRI's already taken that spot.
また3位ですか
3rd again?
新キャラとニューマシンも効果なしか
A new character and a new bike had no effect?
はい で 「CROW」は1位
Okay.
So, CROW is 1st?
でも 順位は同じだが 票差は縮まってる
The ranks are the same, but the vote counts have gotten closer.
そうっすか
I see.
じゃあ 最悪でも1か月後には必ず1位取りますよ
Then, at the very least,
I'll probably get first place in a month.
1か月後
A month? Oh, the front cover color spread.
ああ 巻頭カラーか
From the day I got the idea for a new bike,
ニューマシンのアイデアが出たその日から
それに またがったGIRIの見開き扉に取りかかってます
I already started drawing a color spread of GIRI straddling it.
随分 早くからやってんだな
Getting a really early head start?
にしても1か月ってかけすぎなんじゃ
Isn't it a bit much to spend a whole month drawing it?
そのくらい気合い入れなきゃ「CROW」は抜けないって事ですよ
That's how much effort I'll need to put in to surpass CROW.
なるほど
I see.
巻頭カラーか
A front cover color spread, huh?
羨ましいな
I'm jealous.
「PCP」はこの前やったばかりだし
Well, we did just have one for PCP.
I thought you'd say that,
そう言うだろうと思って
副編集長にカラーもらえるよう申請しておいたよ
so I petitioned the Assistant Chief Editor for a color page.
本当ですか
Really?!
Yeah.
巻頭は難しいが センターカラーなら
A front cover is tough, but I can get you a colored center page instead.
新妻君が最終回を描き始めるまでのどこかでくれると約束してくれた
He promised to give me one before
Niizuma finishes drawing his final chapter.
やった
All right!
センターでもありがたいです
I'm grateful for just a center page!
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
新キャラΣの登場にかけてたのに それでも届かなかった
We bet everything on the introduction of the new character, Sigma,
but even then we didn't catch up to him.
恐らくこのセンターカラーが最後のチャンス
This colored center page will most likely be our last chance!
頑張ってくれよ
Do your best!
新妻君の連続1位を止めるのは
The ones who'll stop Niizuma's first
place run will be you, Ashirogi Mutou!
亜城木夢叶だ
はい
Yes!
連続1位か
First place run, huh?
いや 新妻さんこれで10週連続1位だろ
Well, Niizuma's gotten first place ten weeks in a row by now, right?
本来なら ここで「CROW」はあと10週でまとめて終わるはずだったんだよな
By the original agreement,
he would've already gotten permission to wrap up CROW in the next 10 weeks and then end it.
Yeah.
なんか俺たちって 新妻さんから見れば
To Niizuma, aren't we just nuisances getting in his way of ending CROW?
ただ 「CROW」が終わるのを邪魔してるやつなんじゃ
そうでもないらしいぞ
That doesn't seem to be the case.
そうですか みんなが票を伸ばしてきていてうれしいです
Really?!
I'm glad everyone is getting more votes!
I... see.
そうか うれしいか
So, you're happy about it.
はい そうじゃなきゃ面白くありません スリリング
Yes!
It wouldn't be interesting otherwise.
It's thrilling!
この状況で1位を取り続けて終わらせられるのが最高にかっこいいです
If I can continue to get first place in this situation, I can end this in the coolest possible way!
そんな事を
He said that?
僕も新妻君の鼻を明かしてやりたい
I want to outwit Niizuma as well.
We'll definitely surpass him!
絶対に抜いてやろう
はい
Right!
June 24, Friday
「正義の三肩」巻頭カラー1位取れるか
Can Seigi no Mikata get first place with a front cover color spread?
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
2016, 4th week of June
Weekly "Jack"
Survey Report
勝負
This is it.
Takahama
2位ですか
2nd, huh?
So, the front cover we pinned our hopes on wasn't good enough.
勝負の巻頭カラーでも駄目でしたか
ほ ほんともう少しだったんだ
It was really close, I'm telling you.
うれしいです
I'm happy.
2位なんて 初めてですから
It's the first time I've ever gotten 2nd place.
ああ そうか
Oh, I see.
新連載1回目じゃなく 連載2年以上での2位
Getting 2nd place on a chapter that isn't your first one, for a serialization that's not even two years old.
すごいな
That's impressive indeed.
でも 新妻さんが「CROW」の最終回を描くまで5週ありますから
There's still five weeks to go before Niizuma begins to draw his final chapter, though.
まだ 諦めません
I won't give up just yet!
高浜君
Takahama.
王道バトルマンガ以外で 次の天下を取るのは
The next non-mainstream manga to rise to the top won't be Ashirogi Mutou's,
亜城木夢叶じゃなく 僕です
it'll be mine!
高浜君 2位っすか
So Takahama got 2nd, huh?
ああ 惜しかった
Yeah, it was close.
いや ある意味よかったぜ
I'm glad, actually.
Because now, my front cover color spread will be the one to overtake Niizuma next week!
これで新妻師匠を抜くのは 来週の俺の巻頭カラーになったんだからな
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
福田さん
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Fukuda put a ton of effort into this.
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
Super Exciting
Color Page
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
すげえ 気合い入ってんな
Yeah.
1か月かけただけの事はある
He drew it for a whole month.
Fukuda
July 1, Friday
来た 祝杯の用意
Here it is!
Get the toast ready!
Fukuda here!
はい 福田
Huh? 2nd?
2位
くそーっ
Dammit!
おい 福田君
Hey, Fukuda?
何 開けてんだ バカ
Why did you open it, stupid?!
すいません
I'm sorry!
福田君は悔しがっていたけど「CROW」とはまだ70票差
Fukuda may feel bitter about it, but
CROW won with a full 70 vote margin.
ニューマシンはこの回で出すべきだったな
He should've brought out the new bike in this chapter instead.
せっかくの巻頭カラーなのに インパクトが足りなかった
It didn't have enough impact to live up to the front cover.
何ですか 偉そうに
Hey, get off your high horse.
平丸君の「僕通」も全然上がらないじゃないですか
Hiramaru's Never Reaching You ranking didn't improve at all.
そうなんだよなー
Tell me about it.
平丸君の作品は 絵をうまくしても意味なかったのかなー
I suppose there was no point in trying to make his art better.
でも こうなると「CROW」の終了は誰にも止められないんじゃ
But at this rate, nobody can stop CROW from ending.
We still have four weeks!
A toast
for victory!!
Reach for
the top!
Color Spread!
Road Racer
Fukuda Shinta
まだ4週あるだろ
それはそうですけど
Yes, but...
In Issue 34, right before Niizuma begins his final chapter,
新妻君が 最終回に取りかかる直前の34号で
PCP will have a colored center page.
「PCP」のセンターカラーが決まった
あるいは そこで
Maybe that's where it'll happen.
「GIRI」が巻頭カラーで「CROW」を抜けなかった事を考えると
If GIRI couldn't beat CROW even with a front cover color spread,
センターカラーってだけで1位を取りにいくのはきついか
beating him with just a colored
center page seems really tough.
I think your color pages are better than Fukuda's, though.
でも 福田さんのカラーより
サイコーのカラーの方が魅力あると俺は思うけど
そうじゃなくてさ
That's not it.
Can't we do something special with the color page?
カラーを使って何か仕掛けできないかな
「PCP」ならではの
Something only a series like PCP can do.
A setup like only PCP can do?
「PCP」ならではの仕掛け
はい
Yes.
Um,
えっと 例えば 3Ｄメガネをかけると何か飛び出して見えるとか
how about making something pop out only when you wear 3D glasses?
それじゃ わざわざ読者に3Dメガネ用意してもらわなきゃならないし
That means we'd have to provide the 3D glasses to the readers.
大体3Dの絵なんか描けるかよ
Besides, can you even draw something in 3D?
そっか そうだよな
I see.
Yeah, you're right.
うまく アイデアがまとまらないんですけど
I don't really have an idea for it,
内容とカラー扉をシンクロさせた話作りっていうか
but somehow having the content of the chapter synced up in some way with the color page...
発想は面白いが 難しいぞ
That's an interesting concept, but hard to pull off.
でも 何かできたらすごいですよね
It'd be amazing if we could, though.
Yeah.
確かにそれが「PCP」ならではのトリックにつながればすごいと思うが
If you can tie it in with a PCP-like scheme, that'd be great.
あと4週しかないんだ
We only have 4 weeks left.
I'll think of something.
最悪でもセンターカラーで
At least with our colored center page...
You don't have much time.
あまり時間はないぞ
分かってます
I know.
Mashiro
服部さんにああは言ったものの
I was so confident in front of Hattori, but it's too hard.
駄目だー 何も出てこねぇ
I've got nothing!
どうする 時間もないしカラーで仕掛けるのは もう
What'll we do?
We're out of time, and it's too late to set something up with the color page.
いや ギリギリまで諦めない
No.
Let's dig in our heels until the last minute.
We'll do something with the color page.
カラーページは何とかする
ギリギリまで考えようぜ
Let's think about it until the last minute!
July 6, Wednesday
Ah, it finally stopped raining.
やっと やんでくれたわー
うわ 空気 重っ
Ugh, it's so depressing in here.
内容とカラー扉をつなげるかあ
Connecting the content and the colored title page...
The more I think about it, the harder it is.
考えれば考えるほど難しいよなあ
きれーい そうだ
How pretty!
I got it!
ねえねえ カラーなんだから空に虹を描いて「2時に何かが起きる」って暗号
Since it's in color, how about you draw a rainbow that's actually a code?
There's seven colors in a rainbow, so it means
something will happen at 7 o'clock! Good, right?
いいと思わない
あ ごめん 単純すぎるよね
Oh, sorry.
That's too simple, isn't it?
香耶ちゃん ありがたいけど 少し黙ってて
Kaya, thank you, but could you keep quiet—
時間か
Time...
サイコー 時計持ってる
Saikou, do you have a watch?
July 8, Friday
自分の部屋に一人でいるマコトか
Makoto alone in his room, huh?
It has a different feel than usual. It's tasteful and cool!
いつもとは違う感じで 渋くてかっこいいな
うん いいよ
I like it.
さすがは 真城君だ
Great work as usual, Mashiro.
This is perfect for the color page,
but what about the chapter itself?
カラーは これでいいが
肝心の話の方は大丈夫か
はい 任せて下さい
Leave it to us.
分かった
Okay.
Call me when the storyboard is done.
じゃあ ネームが出来たらすぐに連絡してくれ
はい お疲れさまです
Okay.
Good work.
服部さん 何も気づいてないな
Hattori didn't notice a thing.
あれで気づく方がおかしいって
It would've been weird if he had!
カラー扉に仕掛け
A trick in the color page.
サイコーの言うとおり こだわって正解だったな
You were right to insist on it.
あとは あの仕掛けを最大限に生かす話作り
Now we just need to make a chapter that will maximize this trick's potential!
Yeah!
これが エイジを抜くラストチャンス
This is our last chance to surpass Eiji!
気合い入れて書く
I'll put everything I have into it!
July 11, Monday
「CROW」が14週連続で1位
CROW has been in first place for 14 weeks in a row.
服部 亜城木君の原稿はどうなってる
Hattori, how is Ashirogi's manuscript coming along?
Well, they were supposed to finish the storyboard today—
はい 今日にはネームが上がると
Incoming call
Takagi Akito
やられたな
You got me.
真城君 先週もらったこの回のカラー扉のコピーあるか
Mashiro, do you have a copy of the color page you gave me last week for this chapter?
はい
Yes.
まさか この扉に仕掛けをしていたとは
Who would have thought the trick was in the color page?
面白いよ
It's good.
カラーである事も生かしている
You're using the color page to your advantage.
00 Mins
9th
この「9日」と「00分」
This "9th" and "00 minutes"...
9th
00 Mins
何かあるのかもと気にはなっていたが
I thought something was fishy about them,
扉絵がΣからの挑戦状になっているとはな
but who'd have thought they were actually a challenge from Sigma!
この形はいい よくやった
This approach is good!
You did well!
これなら「CROW」も抜けるぞ
We can pass CROW with this!
はい
Yes!
この回で「CROW」の上に行く
We'll overtake CROW with this chapter.
自信もある
I'm confident in it.
「CROW」はやめさせない
I won't let him end CROW!
そして「PCP」を常に「CROW」を抑えてトップを走る作品にする
And I'll make PCP the manga that constantly dominates CROW!
してみせる
I'll do it!
do
u
shi
te
da
ro...
i
tsu
mo
so
u
sa
Why, I wonder?
chi
ka
zu
ku
ta
bi
ka
ra
ma
wa
ri
no
yu
me
Whenever I am close to fulfilling my goals, all effort becomes fruitless
ma
e
wo
mu
i
te
shi
ga
mi
tsu
i
te
sou
su
ko
shi
zu
tsu
We walk ahead, hold each other, and with little things
ya
ku
so
no
a
ba
sho
he
to
sa
e
ai
na
ga
ra
we support each other to reach what we promised
ji
shi
n
ga
ta
ri
na
i
to
ki
wa
mu
ne
ni
te
wo
a
te
When we lack confidence, we put a hand to our heart
bo
ku
ra
ga
tsu
zu
t
ta
pe
e
ji
yo
mi
ka
e
so
u
and reread the pages we assembled into a story
kyo
u
ma
de
so
shi
te
a
su
he
to
tsu
zu
i
te
yu
ku
no
sa
They lead up to today and continue into the morrow
ta
i
se
tsu
na
yu
me
ga
ka
na
u
so
no
hi
ma
de
We will always be ourselves
a
ri
no
ma
bo
ku
ra
de
zu
tto...
until the day that our dreams come true
Next Time
Preview
誰が新妻君の連続1位を阻止するんだ
Who will stop Niizuma's run at the top?!
僕は誰にも負けません
I won't lose to anyone!
でも 連載は終わってしまう
But your series will end!
次回 最終話とコメント
Next time: Last Chapter and Comments
Last Chapter and
Comments
My dream right now is to end my manga in an ideal way.
今は理想通り終わらせるのは僕の夢です